# Andrei GRAMAKOV

## **Embedded Systems Engineer**

Last update: 06-Nov-2023

**CONTACT INFO** LINKS

Location: Prague, Czech Republic LinkedIn.com/in/agramakov

E-mail: mail@agramakov.me GitHub.com/an-dr

Phone: +420 725 332 130 Personal Site: agramakov.me

#### **Profile**

I am an electronic engineer focused on embedded systems. My experience includes working in small teams and large multinational corporations in different areas - space, aircraft, IoT, industrial automation, semiconductors. I have strong knowledge of C, C++, and Python and a good understanding of electronics from bits to complex electronic systems.

My experience allows me to develop an effective software architecture and support my team in the development process.

## Skills

Programming languages: C, C++, Python, Assembler, ColorForth

Processor architectures: ARM (STM32 series), AVR8 (ATTiny/ATMega series),

GreenArray F18 (GA144), RISC-V, SPARC (LEON3), Xtensa (ESP32 series)

Communication protocols: ARINC 429, CAN, CIP, I2C, RS-232, RS-422, RS-485, SPI, USB

Tools and technologies: GDB, Microsoft DAP, OpenOCD,

> C++ STL, FreeRTOS, Python OpenCV, NumPy, CI/CD, Docker, GIT, SVN, Bash, PowerShell,

Agile, GitLab, GitHub, Jira, Redmine, SCRUM, SOLID principles

PCB and schematic software: Altium Designer, EAGLE CAD, Proteus, MultiSim, KiCAD

CAD software: Autodesk Inventor, Autodesk AutoCAD, Fusion 360, SolidWorks

Mathematical modelling: MathCAD, MATLAB, Octave, SciPy

Data bases: MS Access, SQL

Professional working proficiency (B2) English language:

Russian language: Native proficiency (C2) Czech language: Elementary proficiency (A1)

Portfolio online: agramakov.me/portfolio

(code examples, open source projects, etc.)

# **Employment History**

Senior Embedded Software Engineer (May 2023 – Now)

Company: 2N TELEKOMUNIKACE, an Axis Company (Prague, Czech Republic)

Activity: Firmware development for NFC card readers, fingerprint sensors and other access control devices.

Integration of the devices with the main unit Linux software.

- **Software architecture development** for a new version of the card reader.
- **Establishing of the Unit Testing environment** and integrating in in the operational process.
- Feature implementation by the customer request (more than 10 new features delivered)

I also caused a significant positive impact for the team culture and work process:

- Revised polished and crystalized the team development workflow according to the AGILE principles.
- **Established an effective information exchange I the team** through a documentation system, established a team book library.
- Actively participating in the integration of the AI technologies in the company development practices

Tasks: - Firmware development

- Extensive debugging
- Code review
- Providing help and support to teammates

Technologies: C/C++; STM32; ARM; NFC; RFID; GIT; SAFe; SCRUM;

Senior Embedded Software Engineer (February 2021 – April 2023)

Company: Rockwell Automation (Prague, Czech Republic)

Activity: Development of firmware for industrial automation computers. In detail:

- Development features by design requirements (about 80 closed stories):
  - Sequence Manager an entity for organizing complex technological processes into easily manageable sequences and subsequently provide step-by-step implementations for each sequence.
  - o Implementation of a new OSAL for a future device
  - Writing unit tests
- Fixing bugs (about 50 fixed and closed exceptions)
- Code Reviewing (more than 100 reviews as the main reviewer)

Besides software development, I have actively engaged in fostering a positive team culture and driving organizational improvements within the company. Some of the key initiatives I have undertaken include:

- **Revamping the New Employee Onboarding Process**: I played a main role in revitalizing the onboarding process for new employees, ensuring a smooth transition for developers worldwide.
- **Creating a Learning-Supportive Environment**: Collaborating with the team lead, I established an environment that promotes continuous learning within the team. This involved organizing regular teamwide learning sessions and allocating dedicated time for individual learning endeavors. I personally led five learning sessions to facilitate knowledge sharing and growth.
- **Enhancing Team Communication and Collaboration**: To foster effective communication and collaboration, I introduced a series of meetings for reviewing team rules, synchronizing efforts at the start of each sprint, and ensuring alignment midway through.
- **Developing an Extensive Team Documentation Space**: Recognizing the importance of easy access to information, I spearheaded the development of a comprehensive team documentation repository. This resource ensures that team members have quick and convenient access to critical information, enabling smoother project execution and knowledge sharing.

Tasks: - Development of MISRA compatible firmware code according to the High-Level documentation

- Development of tests
- Code review
- Providing help and support to teammates

Technologies: C/C++; Python; GIT; ARM; ABOS; OSDP; PLC; MISRA C; MISRA C++; Studio 5000 Logix Designer; Common Industrial Protocol (CIP); SAFe; SCRUM

Embedded Software Engineer (January 2019 - December 2020)

Company: Espressif Systems (Brno, Czech Republic)

Activity: Development of tools and drivers for ESP-based processors. Involved in development of debugging tools like OpenOCD and GDB. Implementing and development of debug module based on DAP protocol; Implementing and developing a USB driver for ESP32-S2 chip based on TinyUSB stack.

Tasks

- Debugging tools development (Debug adapter for ESP-IDF VSCode Extension, OpenOCD)
- Middle-ware driver development (ESP-IDF framework)
- Unit tests development
- Preparing trainings for colleagues

Technologies: C/C++; Python; GIT; ESP-IDF; USB; VSCode Extensions; Powershell; CI; Docker; GitHub; FreeRTOS; TinyUSB; Xtensa; Raspberry; Microsoft DAP; OpenOCD

Embedded Systems Programmer (January 2018 - September 2018)

Company: Scientific Production Enterprise Digital Solutions (Moscow, Russia)

Activity: I worked with SPARC and RISC-V based processors projects, and with Sputnik processor (ARM architecture). I developed libraries to operating with processors and peripherals; developed tests and testing software for developed processors, their peripherals and memory; debugged code with HDL models, FPGA, and prototypes layouts. All developed IC are for spacecraft purposes.

Tasks:

- Processor design verification
- Low-level driver development
- Unit-tests development
- Development of debugging tools

Technologies: C; C++; Python; SVN; GIT; Cadence; SPARC V8; RISC-V; ARM; AMBA; I2C; SPI; RS-232; RS-422; RS-485; SpaceWire; CAN; RTOS; FreeRTOS

Chief Specialist of Flight Test Instrumentation Department (June 2017 - December 2017)

Company: Sukhoi Civil Aircraft (Moscow, Russia)

Activity: I worked with Sukhoi Superjet 100 aircraft. My main duty was preparing the Measuring Onboard Systems for qualification trials. I programmed aircraft systems according to sensors set, developed SQL databases, wrote Python programs for information processing, and worked with measure sensors and tools

Tasks:

- Preparing hardware and software for coming trials
- Modeling trials and troubleshooting on aviation simulator
- Development of UI for trials
- Sensor nomenclature accounting
- Sensor database development

Technologies: C#/XAML; Visual Studio; MS Access; Python; MySQL; Entity relationship diagram (ERD); Acra KAM-500; ARINC 429; AFDX; Thermal Sensors.

Electronics Engineer (September 2015 - July 2018)

Company: Bauman Moscow State Technical University (Moscow, Russia)

Activity: My main area was in space data processing and recognition of the space satellites data. In parallel with work projects, I was doing image recognition research.

Tasks:

- Research and development in space imagery (image recognition)
- Development of experiments and experimental stands in support of current research

Technologies: Python; SciPy; OpenCV; Visual Studio; Eclipse; Octave; MATLAB; Autodesk Inventor; CCD devices; IR-, Vis-, UF- imagery devices; Raspberry Pi; ARM; STM32; CANbus; SPI; I2C; RS-232

Electronics Engineer (August 2012 - September 2015)

Company: Research Institute of Radio-electronic techniques (BMSTU) (Moscow, Russia)

**Activity:** My work in the Research Institute was in a field of optoelectronic imagery systems for spacecraft and providing research in space satellite imagery systems.

Tasks:

- Preparing on-ground demonstration of the satellite's (Chibis-M) system with our modification
- Research and development in space imagery (image recognition)
- Teaching Electronic Components Course for Bauman students

Technologies: C/C++, ColorForth, Visual Studio, AtmelStudio, Autodesk Inventor, MATLAB, Stack architecture processors, CCD devices, Arduino, AVR, CANbus.

## **Education**

Master's degree / Specialist degree (September 2007 - Juli 2013)

#### **Bauman Moscow State Technical University**

Specialty: Radio-Electronic Systems and Devices with Specialization in Laser Location and Communication Systems Thesis: "Development of Microsatellite's Onboard Hardware Complex"

Post-Graduate Program (September 2013 - November 2017, not completed)

**Bauman Moscow State Technical University** 

Thesis: "Unified Radio- and Optoelectronic Remote Sensing"

### Personal

Personal characteristics: positive, enthusiastic, open-minded, collaborative

Hobbies: robotics, wood crafting, art, literature